# Rashmi Sahu

# DevOps Engineer

ĭ rashmisahu656@yahoo.com ↓ 9406772772 ♥ Bhopal 🏲 Indian 💄 Female

#### **₽≡ PROFILE SUMMARY**

I have total 5 years and 9 months of experience wherein 3 years I have experience as DevOps Engineer. For the last three years, I am working as a DevOps Engineer, and have good knowledge of AWS Services like EC2, VPC, Load Balancer, Route 53 and S3.

## My recent skills includes:

- Hands-on knowledge of Source Code Management (Version Control System) tools like GIT and Central Repository GitHub.
- Proficient in developing Continuous Integration.
- Hands-on experience with AWS services like EC2, VPC, Load Balancer, Auto scaling, and S3.
- Actively manage, improve, and monitor cloud infrastructure on AWS, EC2, and S3.
- Created AWS(EC2, VPC, Load Balancer, S3) services by using Terraform.
- · Managed GitHub repositories and permissions, including branching and tagging.
- Strong automation skills using Shell Scripting, Powershell.
- Experience in Jenkins, Gitlab/GitHub.
- Experience with ticketing tools such as jira.
- Solid understanding of system performance and monitoring.
- Have used Agile and Scrum methodology.
- Highly motivated, quality-conscious self-starter that requires little to no supervision.
- Strong communication skills with an ability to relay incident details expeditiously, concisely, and accurately.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

Linux, AWS, GIT, GitHub, Terraform, Ansible, Docker, Jenkins, Kubernetes, Shell Scripting (HTML 5.0, Bootstrap, Knowledge of CSS 3)

Basic knowledge of SQL.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### DevOps Engineer, Microtechnologies India

Apr 2020 – present Bhopal, India

- Test, build, design, deployment, and ability to maintain continuous integration and continuous delivery process using tools like Jenkins, Maven, GIT, etc.
- Ability to automate test and deploy the code and monitor.
- Work in close coordination with the development and operations team such that the application is in line with performance according to the customer's expectation.
- Building and setting up new development tools and infrastructure.
- Working on ways to automate and improve development and release processes testing and
  examining code written by others and analysing results working with software developers
  and software engineers to ensure that development follows established processes and
  works as intended.

#### Worked as Team Leader, Technical Support, Solaris Infotech Solution Pvt Ltd

Aug 2017 – Mar 2020

Delhi, India

- Worked as technical Support for School Clients. My team has 6 members.
  The product was SISPL School ERP.
- Role
  - To install and setup software in the client system and make it ready for use.
  - MS SQL was used as a database. I use to guide my team if they get stuck.
  - Listen to client needs and share changes with the project manager for modification in the software.
  - Provide training to new joiners.

- Troubleshooting and testing of new setup.

# PROJECT DETAILS

### Project 1, E-Commerce

An E-commerce project is an online purchasing platform with a user-friendly interface.

Technologies: VPC, Private Subnet, Public Subnet, Internet Gateway, Route Table, NAT Gateway, EC2, Cloud Watch.

Role: My role in this project is to create infrastructure to deploy the software so that it can work seamlessly.

Project2, Deployment of website modules

Description: Website hosting through automation, CI/CD

Technologies: GIT, GitHub, Jenkins, Docker

Role: Created free style CI/CD pipeline for automation

Project3, End to End CI/CD Project of Java

**Description:** Deployment of web based application using CI/CD pipeline **Technologies:** Docker, Jenkins, Nexus, SonarQube, datree, Helm, Kubernetes

Role: Created free style CI/CD pipeline for automation and E-mail notification also configured

Project4, Static website hosting using S3 bucket

Descriptoin: Static website which is used by end users

Technologies: AWS S3

Role: Deployed static website using S3

**Project5,** Tic-Tac-Toe(Designed in Java)

**Description:** This project is basically developed in java which is deployed through Jenkins

Technologies: GIT, GitHub, Jenkins, Ansible, Docker

 $\textbf{Role:} \ It is online \ room \ rent \ project \ which \ is \ developend \ on \ Java, \ I \ created \ automated \ CI/CD \ pipeline \ for \ this \ project \ project \ automated \ CI/CD \ pipeline \ for \ this \ project \ pro$ 

wherein I used GIT, GitHub, Jenkins, Maven, Ansible, Docker.

# **EDUCATION**

## Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Communication,

2010 - 2014

Sagar Institute of Science and Technology Secured 78% Bhopal, India

12th, Krishna Public School

2010

Bhilai, India

10th, Maharishi Vidhya Mandir

2008

Mandla, India

# of INTERESTS

**Gardening, Listening to music, Yoga and Meditation. Learning new things.** (Passionate about gardening, maintaining about 20 different plants. I like Listening to music as it gives me a calming effect.)

## DECLARATION

I hereby declare that that all the details provided above are true to the best of my knowledge.

Rashmi Sahu

Bhopal